Donovan Theseira

Full-Stack Software Developer

Phone 858-699-4251 E-mail dt@donovant.me Website www.donovant.me

A consummate, progressing software engineer with 3+ years of experience, who views every new project like a puzzle with unlimited pieces and infinite ways to finding the solution. At SSAI, led the development of a number of new features to give users more access to data and new ways to connect.

Skills

Client Side

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6

Server Side

Java, bash, JSP, C#, Razor

Frameworks

Liferay (6.2 & 7), jQuery, Angular.js, ASP.NET, Bootstrap, EF6, Google Maps

Database Servers

PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MySQL

Gaining Experience

Docker, Jenkins, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Python

jQuery Plugins

jQuery UI, DataTables

Experience

June 2016 - Present

Software Developer I

Science Systems and Applications, Inc (SSAI)

- Worked on implementing unit testing and to help redesign the development life cycle currently being used.
- Led the development of a project which gives the users a way to create and join teams, view data, and "compete" with other users across the world.
- Added pages to the NASA GLOBE Observer App that allows users to create, find, and join a
- Led the development of a project that allows users to view data about Earth's systems.
- Decreased page load times by as much as 30 seconds using asynchronous techniques.
- Key developer in 40% of a major redesign of www.globe.gov, including creating new PostgreSQL functions and making the site more responsive.
- Developed 10% of a major project for NASA, which displayed changing air temperatures during the Eclipse in 2017.

May 2016 – Present

Programming Consultant

Veneklasen Associates

- Implemented a project management web-application using C# and the Entity Framework.
- Created a MSSQL database, hosted on Azure, with continuous integration.

Education

September 2011 – June 2016 California State Polytechnic University, Pomona

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems

Projects

SmartMirror App written using Node.is, which calls a number of APIs that retrieves weather, market, currently playing spotify data and also retrieves upcoming calendar events. Using the Dark Sky API for the 7 days forecast, CryptoCompare for the current cryptocurrency prices, IEX trading for the current stock market prices, Spotify API to access the users current playing song and current position, and finally using the Google APIs to access the calendar data. Also using Mocha and Chai for testing the server.